[
  {
    "question": "Which of these UK prime ministers never served as foreign secretary?",
    "answer1": "Winston Churchill",
    "answer2": "Anthony Eden",
    "answer3": "Harold MacMillan",
    "answer4": "Alex Douglas-Home",
    "correctAnswer": "Winston Churchill"
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1718, which pirate died in battle off the coast of what is now North Carolina?",
    "answer1": "Blackbeard",
    "answer2": "Calico Jack",
    "answer3": "Captain Kidd",
    "answer4": "Bartholomew Roberts",
    "correctAnswer": "Blackbeard"
  },
  {
    "question": "What Shakespeare character says, \"Something is rotten in the state of Denmark\"?",
    "answer1": "Marcellus",
    "answer2": "Hamlet",
    "answer3": "Horatio",
    "answer4": "Laertes",
    "correctAnswer": "Marcellus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following men does not have a chemical element named for him?",
    "answer1": "Isaac Newton",
    "answer2": "Enrico Fermi",
    "answer3": "Albert Einstein",
    "answer4": "Niels Bohr",
    "correctAnswer": "Isaac Newton"
  },
  {
    "question": "What best-selling author was born Howard Allen O'Brien?",
    "answer1": "Anne Rice",
    "answer2": "J.K. Rowling",
    "answer3": "E.L James",
    "answer4": "Toni Morrison",
    "correctAnswer": "Anne Rice"
  },
  {
    "question": "What letter must appear on the beginning of the registration number of all non-military aircraft in the U.S.?",
    "answer1": "N",
    "answer2": "O",
    "answer3": "F",
    "answer4": "S",
    "correctAnswer": "N"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the TV series \"The Brady Bunch,\" what is Carol Brady's maiden name?",
    "answer1": "Tyler",
    "answer2": "Franklin",
    "answer3": "Nelson",
    "answer4": "Johnson",
    "correctAnswer": "Tyler"
  },
  {
    "question": "The U.S. icon \"Uncle Sam\" was based on Samuel Wilson who worked during the War of 1812 as a what?",
    "answer1": "Meat inspector",
    "answer2": "Historian",
    "answer3": "Mail man",
    "answer4": "Weapons mechanic",
    "correctAnswer": "Meat inspector"
  },
  {
    "question": "Now used to refer to a cat, the word \"tabby\" is derived from the name of a district of what world capital?",
    "answer1": "Baghdad",
    "answer2": "Cairo",
    "answer3": "New Delhi",
    "answer4": "Jakarta",
    "correctAnswer": "Baghdad"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these ships was not one of the three taken over by colonists during the Boston Tea Party?",
    "answer1": "William",
    "answer2": "Eleanor",
    "answer3": "Darthmouth",
    "answer4": "Beaver",
    "correctAnswer": "William"
  },
  {
    "question": "Though today it's treated like a treasure, what famous painting was once cut into enlarge a doorway?",
    "answer1": "The Last Supper",
    "answer2": "The Birth of Venus",
    "answer3": "Guernica",
    "answer4": "Detroit Industry",
    "correctAnswer": "The Last Supper"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the periodic table, there are four different elements named after what?",
    "answer1": "A Swedish mining village",
    "answer2": "Antoine Lavoisier's pet cat",
    "answer3": "A moon of Neptune",
    "answer4": "Marie Curie's maiden name",
    "correctAnswer": "A Swedish mining village"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not the title of a country song released by Netflix phenomenon Joe Exotic, aka the \"Tiger King\"?",
    "answer1": "Big-Hearted Cat",
    "answer2": "I Saw a Tiger",
    "answer3": "Here Kitty Kitty",
    "answer4": "King of the Beast",
    "correctAnswer": "Big-Hearted Cat"
  },
  {
    "question": "Although he and his wife never touched a light switch for fear of being shocked, who was the first president to have electricity in the White House?",
    "answer1": "Benjamin Harrison",
    "answer2": "Andrew Jackson",
    "answer3": "Chester A. Arthur",
    "answer4": "Ulysses S. Grant",
    "correctAnswer": "Benjamin Harrison"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these cetaceans is classified as a \"toothed whale\"?",
    "answer1": "Sperm whale",
    "answer2": "Minke whale",
    "answer3": "Gray whale",
    "answer4": "Humpback whale",
    "correctAnswer": "Sperm whale"
  },
  {
    "question": "How old is our solar system?",
    "answer1": "4.57 billion years",
    "answer2": "3.62 billion years",
    "answer3": "2.12 billion years",
    "answer4": "6.72 billion years",
    "correctAnswer": "4.57 billion years"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many moons are currently orbiting Jupiter?",
    "answer1": "79",
    "answer2": "12",
    "answer3": "87",
    "answer4": "34",
    "correctAnswer": "79"
  },
  {
    "question": "What year did the longest tennis match take place at Wimbledon?",
    "answer1": "2010",
    "answer2": "1972",
    "answer3": "1998",
    "answer4": "2002",
    "correctAnswer": "2010"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was named the \"deadliest football match in history\"?",
    "answer1": "Peru vs Argentina's 1964 game",
    "answer2": "Brazil vs Argentina 1984's game",
    "answer3": "England vs Scotland 1991's game",
    "answer4": "Serbia vs Albanina 2005's game",
    "correctAnswer": "Peru vs Argentina's 1964 game"
  },
  {
    "question": "What magazine began publishing its annual list of the 500 most-successful companies in the US in 1955?",
    "answer1": "Fortune",
    "answer2": "Forbes",
    "answer3": "Times",
    "answer4": "New York Times",
    "correctAnswer": "Fortune"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the subject of the first color photograph?",
    "answer1": "Tartan ribbon",
    "answer2": "Apple",
    "answer3": "A family",
    "answer4": "A soccer ball",
    "correctAnswer": "Tartan ribbon"
  },
  {
    "question": "The bands Whitesnake and Rainbow were both splinter groups from what British rock band?",
    "answer1": "Deep Purple",
    "answer2": "Black Sabbath",
    "answer3": "The Who",
    "answer4": "Led Zeppelin",
    "correctAnswer": "Deep Purple"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the TV series \"Lost\", which airline's plane crashed?",
    "answer1": "Oceanic airlines",
    "answer2": "American airlines",
    "answer3": "Spirit airlines",
    "answer4": "Delta airlines",
    "correctAnswer": "Oceanic airlines"
  },
  {
    "question": "The planet Uranus was originally named what?",
    "answer1": "George's star",
    "answer2": "Callisto",
    "answer3": "Europa",
    "answer4": "Titania",
    "correctAnswer": "George's star"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the smallest horse in the world?",
    "answer1": "Fallabella",
    "answer2": "Noma",
    "answer3": "Fjord horse",
    "answer4": "Haflinger",
    "correctAnswer": "Fallabella"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the medical term for earwax?",
    "answer1": "Cerumen",
    "answer2": "Mucus",
    "answer3": "Flatus",
    "answer4": "Diaphoresis",
    "correctAnswer": "Cerumen"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did Esther Howland popularize in the US?",
    "answer1": "Valentine's day cards",
    "answer2": "Black Friday sales",
    "answer3": "Fourth of July BBQ",
    "answer4": "Haunted houses during Halloween",
    "correctAnswer": "Valentine's day cards"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the movie \"Batman v Superman\" what poster can be seen in the background as the Waynes are walking out of a movie theater before their mugging?",
    "answer1": "The Mark of Zorro",
    "answer2": "The Shining",
    "answer3": "Witness",
    "answer4": "Wall Street",
    "correctAnswer": "The Mark of Zorro"
  },
  {
    "question": "Frank Sinatra was buried with a bottle of what whiskey?",
    "answer1": "Jack Daniel's",
    "answer2": "Bulleit Bourbon",
    "answer3": "High West Distillery",
    "answer4": "Tyrconnell",
    "correctAnswer": "Jack Daniel's"
  },
  {
    "question": "What ship was commanded by Peter Blood?",
    "answer1": "Arabella",
    "answer2": "Poseidon",
    "answer3": "Titan",
    "answer4": "Alexandria",
    "correctAnswer": "Arabella"
  }
]

